Guide to the Cable 13 Videotapes, 1976-2009 UA.09.13.0008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cable 13 Videotapes
1976-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cable 13 (Television station: Durham, N.C.)
UA.09.13.0008
154 Linear Feet
Duke Union Community Television (Cable 13), Duke's student-run television station, grew out of Freewater Films' video programming group, following the purchase of a television camera. Cable 13 was the first student-owned and student-run television station in the country. Cable 13 became an official committee of the Duke University Union in 1976. It broadcasts on the Duke campus cable system. The collection consists of videocassettes and videotapes of events recorded at and around Duke between 1976 and 2009. It includes such figures as William S. Burroughs, Allen Ginsberg, Nikki Giovanni, Juanita Kreps, Terry Sanford, Ralph Nader, and Elie Wiesel, as well as performances from Dance Black, the Duke Symphony Orchestra, the Duke Wind Symphony, the Firesign Theatre, Jerry Garcia, and Hoof'n'Horn. Other events include men's and women's basketball, women's crew, football, soccer, men's and women's volleyball, and Joe College Weekend, as well as news and talk shows.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Use of audiotapes and videotapes from this collection requires the creation of reference copies. Reference copies for some materials may have been made, and if a reference copy exists, it is noted in this finding aid. To arrange for the creation of reference copies of other items, please contact University Archives staff. Although these recordings are now stored in a stable environment, their condition and playback quality is unknown.
Provenance
The Cable 13 Videotapes were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1981, 2014, and 2016; accession numbers UA81-42, UA2014-0067, UA2016-0027.
Historical Note
Duke Union Community Television (Cable 13), Duke's student-run television station, grew out of Freewater Films' video programming group, following the purchase of a television camera. Cable 13 was the first student-owned and student-run television station in the country. Cable 13 became an official committee of the Duke University Union in 1976. It broadcasts on the Duke campus cable system.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of videocassettes and half-inch open reel videotapes of events recorded at and around Duke, as well as student-produced content, between 1976 and 2009. Interviewees and notable figures include William S. Burroughs, Allen Ginsberg, Nikki Giovanni, Juanita Kreps, Joseph Kruzel, Henry Kyemba, Peter Orlovsky, Terry Sanford, Daniel Schorr, Ralph Nader, Elie Wiesel, and Dave Thomas. Performances include Dance Black, the Duke Symphony Orchestra, the Duke Wind Symphony, Hoof'n'Horn, the Firesign Theatre, Jerry Garcia, Lotte Goslar's Pantomime Circus, and Roger McGuinn and Thunderbyrd. Events include men's and women's basketball, women's crew, football, soccer, men's and women's volleyball, and Joe College Weekend. Also include are news, talk shows, panel discussions, and many other shows.
Videotapes; Lotte Goslar's Pantomime Circus; McGuinn, Roger; Schorr, Daniel, 1916-; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997; Giovanni, Nikki; Kreps, Juanita Morris; Kyemba, Henry, 1939-; Duke University. Dance Black; Duke University. Symphony Orchestra; Firesign Theatre (Performing group); Garcia, Jerry, 1942-; Duke University -- Soccer; Duke University -- Volleyball -- Women's.; Duke University -- Volleyball; Duke University Wind Symphony; Duke University -- Joe College Weekend; Duke University -- Football; Duke University -- Crew -- Women's; Duke University -- Basketball; Cable 13 (Television station: Durham, N.C.); Burroughs, William S., 1914-; Sanford, Terry; Wiesel, Elie, 1928-; Nader, Ralph; Thomas, Dave, 1932-2002
- Accession A81-42
  Arrangement note
  Each show or project was give a volume number when it was recorded. The volume number can refer to a single tape, or it can refer to multiple tapes that make up a show or project. That numbering system has been maintained, and tapes are stored in numerical order by volume number. To facilitate research and the location of tapes, all tapes are presented in this finding aid in alphabetical order by title with their corresponding box and volume numbers.
  - American Ballet. Page Auditorium, 1978 Feb. 17, lb: (Box 10, Volume 116)
  - Anderson, Jack. Page Auditorium, 1976 Nov. 17, lb: (Box 2, Volume 20)
  - Another Saturday Night, undated., 3 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 97)
  - Anything Goes, 1977 Apr. 20, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 96)
  - Anything Goes: Student Locator, undated, lb: (Box 2, Volume 18)
  - Anything Goes: Student Locator, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 7, Volume 84)
  - Arnold, Jim. Party, 1976 Nov. 19, lb: (Box 10, Volume 133)
  - ASDU Candidates, 1977 Nov. 2, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 7, Volume 76)
  - ASDU Presidential Forum, 1977 Nov. 9, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 7, Volume 75)
  - ASDU Presidential Forum, 1978 Nov. 8, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 7, Volume 77)
  - ASDU Symposium: Presidents, undated, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 1, Volume 5)
  - As-Salaam Alaikum: Do You Thank Allah for Another Day, 1976 Nov. 29, lb: (Box 10, Volume 117)
  - Atlanta Ballet, 1978 Apr. 11, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 9, Volume 103)
  - Barkin, Alan. Party, 1976 Oct. 31, lb: (Box 10, Volume 115)
  - Basketball: Banks, Dennard, Scrimmage, undated, lb: (Box 10, Volume 118)
  - Basketball: Duke vs. North Carolina State University, 1977 Jan. 22, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 4, Volume 36)
  - Basketball: Duke vs. St. Josephs, 1977 Apr. 5, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 4, Volume 38)
  - Basketball: Duke vs. UVA, 1977 Feb. 9, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 86)
  - Basketball: Duke vs. Wake Forest University, 1977 Feb. 2, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 4, Volume 39)
  - Basketball: Duke vs. Washington College, 1977 Nov. 29, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 5, Volume 40)
  - Best Years of our Lives, 1977 Feb. 21, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 5, Volume 60)
  - Bird, Tony, 1976 Nov. 23, lb: (Box 9, Volume 105)
  - Campbell, Will, 1977 Jan. 31, lb: (Box 6, Volume 71)
  - Celebration of Spring, 1976, lb: (Box 10, Volume 119)
  - Celebration of Spring, 1976, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 3, Volume 31)
  - Celebration of Spring: Highlights, 1976, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 3, Volume 28)
  - Celebration of Spring: Roving camera, crafts, 1976 Apr. 23, lb: (Box 3, Volume 29)
  - Celebration of Spring: Various Groups, 1976 Apr. 23, lb: (Box 3, Volume 30)
  - Citizen Flash, 1976, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 94)
  - Cousins, Norman: Speech, Closing, UNC Survival Symposium, 1976 Apr. 2, lb: (Box 2, Volume 16)
  - Dance Black, 1980 Feb. 27, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 9, Volume 111)
  - Dance Black Concert: Pamoja Sisi Kucheza, 1976 Mar. 18, lb: (Box 1, Volume 6)
  - Dance Black: Essence of Black. Page Auditorium, 1976 Feb. 17, lb: (Box 10, Volume 120)
  - Doc on Docs: Anne Hodges, undated, lb: (Box 10, Volume 122)
  - Documentary Idea, 1977, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 87)
  - Duke Campaign '77: Candidate Advertising spots, 1977 Feb. 19, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 3, Volume 26)
  - Duke Campaign '77: ASDU Election Forum, 1977 Feb. 2, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 7, Volume 74)
  - Duke Dance, 1976 Nov. 16, lb: (Box 1, Volume 13)
  - Duke Dance: Leap Year Dance Show, 1976 Feb. 29, lb: (Box 1, Volume 14)
  - Duke Symphony, 1977 Oct. 14, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 5, Volume 58)
  - Duke Symphony, 1978 Dec., 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 92)
  - Duke Symphony Orchestra, 1977 Mar. 2, lb: (Box 1, Volume 7)
  - Duke Wind Symphony, 1977 Mar. 26, lb: (Box 1, Volume 8)
  - Duke Wind Symphony, 1977 Nov. 19, lb: (Box 1, Volume 9)
  - Durden, Robert, 1978 Mar. 10, lb: (Box 10, Volume 123)
  - Durham Street Fair and Toilet Tape, undated, lb: (Box 10, Volume 124)
  - Election '76: Joel Smith interview, 1976 Nov. 2, lb: (Box 10, Volume 125)
  - Election '76: Terry Sanford interview, undated, lb: (Box 10, Volume 126)
  - Energy You Save May be your Own, 1977 Dec. 16, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 6, Volume 65)
  - Fashion comes to Duke: Nina Hyde interview, undated, lb: (Box 10, Volume 127)
  - Firesign Theatre, undated, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 5, Volume 59)
  - Football: Duke vs. Clemson, 1976 Oct. 16., lb: (Box 4, Volume 35)
  - Football: Duke vs. NCSU, 1976, lb: (Box 4, Volume 33)
  - Football: Duke vs. NCSU post-game show, 1976, lb: (Box 4, Volume 34)
  - Football: Duke vs. USC, 1976, lb: (Box 4, Volume 32)
  - Future of Public Broadcasting Seminar, 1979 Jan. 21, lb: (Box 10, Volume 129)
  - Galloping Guzzler, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 7, Volume 83)
  - Garcia, Jerry: Concert at Duke University, 1976 Apr. 5, 3 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch (marked "EIAJ standard"). (Box 2, Volume 23)
  - Giovanni, Nikki, 1977 Nov. 10, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 95)
  - Gutman, Herbert. Panel Discussion, 1976 Nov. 8, lb: (Box 2, Volume 15)
  - H-Bomb Concert [Peter Holsapple and the H-Bombs], 1977 Mar. 18, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 9, Volume 100)
    - Reference Copy: DVD. UA81-42-2. (Box 9)
  - Herpes, 1977 Nov., 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 88)
  - Hillside Commercials, undated, lb: (Box 10, Volume 130)
  - Hingston, Sandy: A Song in the Garden, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 6, Volume 63)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1977 Mar. 22, lb: (Box 6, Volume 70)
  - Homecoming. Wallace Wade Stadium, 1976, lb: (Box 10, Volume 131)
  - Housing Shortage at Duke, 1977 Oct. 26, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 93)
  - Hungry for Change: Thoughts from a College Campus, 1982 June, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 9, Volume 112)
  - Joe College: Springfest '77--bands, interviews, beer-chugging contest, 1977 Apr. 15, lb: (Box 10, Volume 134)
  - Joe College: Saturday--Scenes, 1977 Apr. 16, lb: (Box 11, Volume 135)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Interviews with Mark and Seth, 1977 Apr. 17, lb: (Box 11, Volume 136)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Preservation Jazz Co., 1977 Apr. 17, lb: (Box 11, Volume 137)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Roger McGuinn and Thunderbyrd, 1977 Apr. 17, lb: (Box 11, Volume 138)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Southwing and Preservation Jazz. Co., 1977 Apr. 17, lb: (Box 11, Volume 139)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Southwing, 1977 Apr. 17, lb: (Box 11, Volume 140)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Tall Dogs, 1977 Apr. 17, lb: (Box 11, Volume 141)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Tall Dogs, Roger McGuinn and Thunderbyrd, 1977 Apr. 17, lb: (Box 11, Volume 142)
  - Kennedy Interview, undated, lb: (Box 12, Volume none)
  - Klesch, Gary, 1976 Nov. 3, lb: (Box 2, Volume 19)
  - Kolisch and Kertzner Interviews, 1977 Sept. 29, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 3, Volume 27)
  - Kolisch, John: Performance, 1977 Sept. 28, lb: (Box 5, Volume 57)
  - Kreps, Juanita, and Amanda Smith, undated, lb: (Box 1, Volume 10)
  - Kruzel, Joseph: Ford and Carter Foreign Policy, 1976 Oct. 5, lb: (Box 2, Volume 17)
  - Kyemba, Henry: Interview, 1978 Feb. 14, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 6, Volume 67)
  - Kyemba, Henry: Speech, question and answer session, 1978 Feb. 14, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 6, Volume 66)
  - LITE Summer Games, 1982 June 26-27, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 9, Volume 114)
  - Lotte Goslar's Pantomime Circus, 1977 Apr. 6, lb: (Box 11, Volume 143)
  - Lovejoy: Nuclear Energy Debate, undated, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 99)
  - Mann, Glenn E. (Ted): Interview, 1982 July 5, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 9, Volume 113)
  - Mathias, Charles, Senator: Panel Interview, 1977 Nov. 18, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 9, Volume 101)
  - McAlister, Elizabeth, 1976 Apr. 2, lb: (Box 3, Volume 25)
  - Nader, Ralph, 1976 Sept. 29, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch (reel #1 of 3 missing). (Box 5, Volume 46)
  - New Performing Dance Co., 1976 Nov. 30, lb: (Box 1, Volume 11)
  - Paletz, David: Media in the Campaign, undated, lb: (Box 3, Volume 24)
  - Phelps, Jake: Director, University Union, 1978 Apr. 5, lb: (Box 11, Volume 146)
  - Pig Roast: Woods Scene, 1977 Nov. 14, lb: (Box 11, Volume 147)
  - Pig Roast: Caldwell Community College, undated, lb: (Box 11, Volume 148)
  - Pig Roast: Lost Tape #1, undated, lb: (Box 11, Volume 149)
  - Pig Roast: Early Morning Sunrise, undated, lb: (Box 12, Volume none)
  - Pig Roast: Ride in Truck, undated, lb: (Box 12, Volume none)
  - Pigskin Profile, 1978 Oct. 8, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 9, Volume 102)
  - Polo, M. W., undated, lb: (Box 11, Volume 144)
  - Primate Center, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 91)
  - Psychic Research: Mysteries of the Mind, 1977 Nov. 11, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 7, Volume 81)
  - Pure Prairie League: Cameron Hall, 1977 Mar. 18, lb: (Box 5, Volume 41)
  - Reid, Robin: Interview by Chapel and interview with Larry in Jones Bldg, 1977 Dec. 5, lb: (Box 10, Volume 132)
  - Salamon, Lester: Domestic issues in the campaign, 1976 Oct. 19, lb: (Box 2, Volume 22)
  - Sanford, Terry: A talk with Terry Sanford, 1977 Oct. 17, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 6, Volume 64)
    - Reference Copy: VHS. UA81-42-1. (Box 6)
  - Schorr, Daniel: Major Speaker's address on the West Union Quad, 1976 Apr. 21, lb: (Box 7, Volume 73)
  - Schorr, Daniel: Panel Discussion, 1976 Apr. 21, lb: (Box 6, Volume 72)
  - Sidey, Hugh, undated, lb: (Box 2, Volume 21)
  - Soccer II, 1976 Nov. 19, lb: (Box 11, Volume 150)
  - Soccer: Duke vs. UNC-Wilmington, 1976 Oct. 19, lb: (Box 5, Volume 42)
  - Solitaire: Original Music by Dave Feinman and Bill Needell, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 6, Volume 62)
  - Storaska, Frederic, 1978 Sept. 15, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 7, Volume 78)
  - Strategies for Human and Technological Progress: Global Ecological Agriculture, 1977 Mar. 16, lb: (Box 9, Volume 104)
  - Toad the Mime, undated 1977 Feb. 13, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 6, Volume 61)
  - Together After 20 Years, Part 1: Allen Ginsberg, William Burroughs, and Peter Orlorsky at the UNC Chapel Hill Fine Arts Festival, 1977 Mar. 17, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 98)
  - Town and Gown, 1977 Dec. 7, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Volume 93)
  - Turner, Mrs., undated, lb: (Box 11, Volume 151)
  - UNC-Chapel Hill Lab Band and The Duke Jazz Ensemble, 1977 Feb. 8, lb: (Box 1, Volume 3)
  - Volleyball: Duke vs. NCSU, undated, lb: (Box 5, Volume 43)
  - Volleyball: Women's Varsity UNCCH 1976 Oct. 26, lb: (Box 12, Volume 152)
  - Ways of Life, 1977 Mar. 17, lb: (Box 6, Volume 69)
  - Wittles, Martha: Making the invisible visible, 1977 Apr. 12, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 7, Volume 82)
  - Woman's Crew, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 7, Volume 79)
  - Woman's Crew, 1977 Nov. 28 and 1977 Dec. 6, lb: (Box 9, Volume 106)
  - Woman's Crew, 1977 Dec. 6, lb: (Box 12, Volume 153)
  - Women's Tennis: Duke vs. UVA, 1976, lb: (Box 5, Volume 45)
  - Women's Volleyball: Duke vs. UNC-Ch, North Carolina State Volleyball Tournament, 1976 Nov., lb: (Box 5, Volume 44)
  - Women's Volleyball: Duke vs. ECU, 1977 Oct. 11, lb: (Box 12, Volume 154)
  - Women's Volleyball, 1976 Oct. 19, lb: (Box 5, Volume 47)
  - Women's Volleyball: Duke vs. UNC-Ch, 1976 Oct. 11, lb: (Box 12, Volume 155)
  - Yale Alleycats: Cambridge Inn. 1978 Mar. 22, lb: (Box 12, Volume 156)
- Accession UA2014-0067, 1996-1999
  - Ivy Tower Episode 2: Class, 1996 (Box 106)
  - Tangled Up in Blue, 1997 (Box 106)
  - Eye of the Devil: 1998 Video Yearbook (Box 106)
  - Devilosity: 1999 Video Yearbook (Box 106)
- Accession UA2016-0027, 1976-2009; 2
  - One of first Cable 13 tapes - Interview Burroughs, 1976 (Box 103, Audio-reel UA09130008-RR-0001)
  - To Hell with Carolina, 1977 (Box 13, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0001)
    Scope and Contents
    Program Length: n/a; Other notes: Features field hockey interview
  - Jimmy Buffet, 1977 (Box 101, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0002)
    Cable13 tape number: Reel 3 of 3
  - "Thirteen Minutes...", 1977-1978 (Box 92, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0073)
    Program Length: 13mins45secs; Other notes: Interviews around campus: Nuclear power, women at duke, men at duke
  - John Kolisch: The Magic of Hypnotism, 1977 September 28 (Box 13, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0070)
    Program Length: 1:00:00; Cable13 tape number: SP 1B; Other notes: Black and White
  - John Kolisch: The Magic of Hypnotism, 1977 September 28 (Box 13, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0071)
    Program Length: 0:55:00; Cable13 tape number: SP 1C; Other notes: B&W, 2 camera production, switched
  - John Kolisch: The Magic of Hypnotism, 1977 September 28 (Box 13, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0072)
    Program Length: 1:00:00; Cable13 tape number: SP 1A; Other notes: B&W, 2 camera production, switched
  - Buffet, 1977 October 01 (Box 101, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0067)
    Program Length: 53mins; Cable13 tape number: #2; Other notes: Chris Ingrodsen - Prod
  - Jimmy Buffet, 1977 October 01 (Box 101, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0068)
    Program Length: 55mins; Cable13 tape number: Reel 3 of 3; Other notes: Total program time: 1hr 56mins, Ingrodsen
  - Raol Servais Films, 1977 October 31 (Box 13, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0069)
    Program Length: n/a; Other notes: http://www.arts.state.tx.us/video/identify.asp
  - Harmony Band at Page, 1977 December 07 (Box 13, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0064)
    Program Length: 0:52:00; Cable13 tape number: E3; Other notes: Roger Greene, John Ray, Isabel Schaff, Eric Pettigrew, Steve Lett
  - Karla Bonoff at Page, 1977 December 07 (Box 15, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0065)
    Program Length: 0:48:00; Cable13 tape number: E2; Other notes: Roger Greene, John Ray, Isabel Schaff, Eric Pettigrew, Steve Lett
  - "Take 2": Camerawork in Action, 1977 December 12 (Box 13, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0066)
    Program Length: 0:30:00; Other notes: Produced by Jim Benfer, Camera by Steve Izzo
  - Solar Energy: Our Brightest Hope, 1978 April (Box 13, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0074)
    Program Length: 0:24:00; Cable13 tape number: ST 4; Other notes: By Peter Gillon and John Sigenhaler
  - Cable 13 Logos, 1978, 1979 (Box 13, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0081)
    Program Length: 0:10:00; Cable13 tape number: ST 2; Other notes: Logo 1978, Logo 1979, Do not reuse
  - Basketball: Duke vs ECU, 1978 January 28 (Box 92, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0077)
    Program Length: 48mins44secs
  - Cigarettes in Concert, 1978 March 18 (Box 13, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0078)
    Program Length: 0:43:00; Cable13 tape number: E4; Other notes: Greta Nettleton, Dan Hallaw, Lindsay Bundsay, Andy Hemmendinger, Anne Kelley, Isabel Schaff, Steve Lett
  - The Outlaws in Cameron, 1978 October 15 (Box 13, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0079)
    Program Length: n/a; Cable13 tape number: 9009-60-017; Other notes: Redone w. Toaster 3/8/91, Michael McIntyre
  - The Outlaws (Edited), 1978 October 15 (Box 14, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0080)
    Program Length: 1:00:00; Cable13 tape number: E6; Other notes: Roger Greene, Bob Nisse, Doug Deneen, Dale Denanzio, Jim Frost, Kathy Slatton, Jon Perry, Danny Kalish, Chris Inguordsen
  - Men's Basketball - Duke vs. LaSalle, 1978 December 05 (Box 14, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0075)
    Program Length: 1:02:30; Cable13 tape number: 2 of 3; Other notes: CH1
  - Men's Basketball - Duke vs. LaSalle, 1978 December 05 (Box 14, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0076)
    Program Length: 0:31:20; Cable13 tape number: 3 of 3; Other notes: CH1
  - A Look at Blue Devil Soccer, 1979 (Box 15, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0003)
    Program Length: 0:29:19; Cable13 tape number: Tape (1); Other notes: CH1+2, HBO Preview at 22:01
  - A Look at Blue Devil Field Hockey, 1979 (Box 15, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0004)
    Program Length: 0:16:38; Cable13 tape number: Tape (1); Other notes: CH 1+2
  - A look at Blue Devil Football & Ballet Dancing, 1979 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0005)
    Program Length: 0:22:22 & 27mins; Cable13 tape number: L 13 / S2; Other notes:
  - David Young's Freewater, 1979, 1980 (Box 26, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0115)
    Program Length: 25mins&12mins; Other notes: David Young's "The Only Reason I Wash Your Brain is to Have a Clean Avenue to Your Heart" starring Wendy Ward, Jack Coleman and Brad Eichwald - 25min (1980) & "The Lost Last Reel of 'The Birth of a Nation" starring Michael Goldstein, Wendy Ward - 12min (1979)
  - Nightwatch, 1979 January 30 (Box 15, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0093)
    Program Length: 0:21:00; Cable13 tape number: ST 5
  - Nightwatch, 1979 January 31 (Box 13, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0094)
    Cable13 tape number: 2 of 8
  - Nightwatch, 1979 February 13 (Box 14, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0086)
    Program Length: 0:21:00; Cable13 tape number: 5 of 8; Other notes: DVC-TV
  - Mike Cross #1, 1979 February 13 (Box 14, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0087)
    Program Length: 0:59:00; Cable13 tape number: 1; Other notes: Producer Doug Deneen
  - Mike Cross #2, 1979 February 13 (Box 15, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0088)
    Program Length: 0:58:00; Cable13 tape number: 2; Other notes: Producer Doug Deneen
  - Mike Cross #3, 1979 February 13 (Box 15, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0089)
    Program Length: 0:18:25; Cable13 tape number: 3; Other notes: Producer Doug Deneen
  - Nightwatch, 1979 February 14 (Box 14, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0090)
    Program Length: 0:21:22; Cable13 tape number: 6 of 8, ST 8
  - Nightwatch, 1979 February 20 (Box 14, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0091)
    Cable13 tape number: 7 of 8
  - Nightwatch, 1979 February 21 (Box 14, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0092)
    Program Length: 0:21:00; Cable13 tape number: 8 of 8
  - Mary Lou Williams Interview, 1979 March 07 (Box 17, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0095)
    Program Length: 10mins; Cable13 tape number: I 1; Other notes: black & white interview by J. Perry
  - Music in the Garden with John Humphrey, 1979 March 09 (Box 15, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0096)
    Program Length: 0:24:00; Cable13 tape number: E10; Other notes: No video?
  - Dixie Dregs, 1979 April 17 (Box 29, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0082)
    Cable13 tape number: Tape 1; Other notes: due to audio problem start tape 5-10min into tape at credits
  - Mike Cross, 1979 September 18 (Box 15, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0111)
    Program Length: 0:31:30; Cable13 tape number: E11-A; Other notes: Laura Murdock, Mike Grower, Tom Gibson, Dave Dubow, Steve Lett, Bob Nissen, Doug Deneen, Dave Gieselmann, Ellen Israel, Susan Deaton
  - Mike Cross, 1979 September 18 (Box 15, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0112)
    Program Length: 0:53:00; Cable13 tape number: E11-B; Other notes: Laura Murdock, Mike Grower, Tom Gibson, Dave Dubow, Steve Lett, Bob Nissen, Doug Deneen, Dave Gieselmann, Ellen Israel, Susan Deaton
  - Mike Cross, 1979 September 18 (Box 15, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0113)
    Program Length: 0:54:00; Cable13 tape number: E11-C; Other notes: Laura Murdock, Mike Grower, Tom Gibson, Dave Dubow, Steve Lett, Bob Nissen, Doug Deneen, Dave Gieselmann, Ellen Israel, Susan Deaton
  - Mike Cross, 1979 September 18 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0114)
    Program Length: 0:11:30; Cable13 tape number: E11-D; Other notes: Laura Murdock, Mike Grower, Tom Gibson, Dave Dubow, Steve Lett, Bob Nissen, Doug Deneen, Dave Gieselmann, Ellen Israel, Susan Deaton
  - Dick Cavett, 1979 October 06 (Box 16, Video-cassette UA09130008-Umatic-0101)